

Nepean, Ottawa, ON

**3** 343 297 0095

✓ you.ayassin@gmail.com

yyassin.github.io/Portfolio

yyassin in /yousefy

All links clickable!

## BIOGRAPHY

#### Nice to meet you!

I am a self-driven engineer and developer who strives to continuously innovate and refine computer systems. I have a passion for empowering people and making their lives more fulfilling through fun and fluid experiences.

# **SKILLS**

GraphOL

Algorithm Firebase
Design NodeJS
Data
Structures React & Vue
MongoDB Django

LANGUAGES
Python

Javascript
HTML & CSS

Java

# **PROJECTS**

#### ILLUMI

Node, Mongo, GraphQL, React, Electron

A **social app** geared towards students. Boasts a beautiful UI, live room-messaging, calendar-events, lessons and more.

### STOCKPREME & FINENHANCE

JavaFX & Tkinter, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy

**Financial apps** that integrate banking with the stock market. Live stocks, currency exchanges, transactions, etc.

### MEETSPORT

Node, Mongo, Websockets, EJS

**Networking app** made for athletes. Provides the ability to find, connect, chat and coordinate play sessions.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### STEM TUTOR & INSTRUCTOR

Electron

OCDSB & PASSIONATE-MINDS | Sep 2016 - Present

Taught high-school curriculum and helped numerous students learn the fundamentals of math & science.

Developped strategic plans for STEM related activities.

Held meetings with course instructors and colleagues to coordinate lesson strategies. Aided in founding a new web-platform with friends to reach a larger audience.

### RESTAURANT CREW

McDonald's Incorporation | Jul 2019 - Present

Maintained high standards of customer service during high-volume, fast-paced operations.

### **STRENGTHS**

Born in Canada. Learned Arabic from birth and studied French academically.







Oral & Written Communication

Reliable & Consistent

Commited to Learning

Team Building

## **EDUCATION**

B. Eng in Computer Systems Engineering

Carleton University | 2019 - 2024

Combining hardware and software to design and refine integrated computer systems for applications in areas such as robotics, artificial-intelligence and cloud computing.

### RECOGNITION

- OCDSB | Governor General Medal
   Awarded for highest average upon graduation.
- WATERLOO | Math Contest Champion
  Awarded for highest-acheiving performance.

# CERTIFICATION

- LINKEDIN | Python

  Certified python script developer.
- LINKEDIN | Web Developer (NodeJS, HTML, CSS)

  Certified knowledge-base in the listed languages.